hamidashita kaze wo atsumete mitai na
I want to try and gather the unrestrained winds
nami no saki tsutatte kanata e kaketeku
I'll run toward the horizon alongside the wave crests
kakugo wa kimatteru
I've made my decision
michi wa tookutemo
even if there's a long way to go on that road
egaita mirai e tsudzuiteru
I'll continue towards the future I've planned
toki ga bokura wo sekashite kodou ga supiido agetetta
time rushes us, the heartbeat speeds up
yume no naka de mezametemo onaji hikari wo sagashita
when I woke in the middle of a dream, I kept searching for that same light
kagayaku hoshizora no shita kazoekirenai seiza to kage
under the shining star-lit sky, with countless constellations and shadows
sono saki ni kimi wa nani wo nani wo mitsumete iru darou
there was something beyond that, what were you gazing at?
nani wo mitsumete iru darou
what were you gazing at?
Where...?
Where... am I?
Shock, the Closed Door
All right! I'm up for it today again!
However, there haven't been
any flashy missions around here lately.
Come on! It's unbelievable, right?!
Yeah, well...
Lately, I'm dead tired
from doing nothing but training.
Sakura!
Naruto!
There's someone who's got
too much time on his hands!
What's that?! Speak for yourself.
No matter how I look at it,
you are just helping the shop.
What happened
to Shikamaru and Choji?
On a mission with Asuma-sensei!
Oh, I wanted to go on a mission, too!
While Ino was down with a cold,
everyone went on urgent missions.
And now I'm completely recovered!
What am I going to do
with all my fighting spirit?
Why don't you use that fighting spirit
in some training?
That's what you think!
In my family, if you don't have
a training partner,
then they make up some reason
for you to help out with the shop!
They must know that if you're alone,
you'll skip training, eh?
Hey! Don't say something
that could hurt a person's reputation!
I do it properly by myself.
Naruto...
Stop it, Shino! Don't surprise me!
Uzumaki Naruto, Yamanaka Ino.
The Hokage is asking
for both of you.
What? Me, too?
By the way, I've also been ordered
to go along with you guys.
Ino, me and Shino?
Demon of Ocean causing disturbance...?
Yes, literally a demon in the ocean.
It seems to be causing the disturbance
happening in the remote Land of Sea.
What's wrong?
You'll go for me, won't you?
Of course.
— Shizune.
— Yes!
— Explain.
As you can see,
the Land of Sea is made up
of a group of islands of various sizes.
Recently in that area, their only means
of transportation, ships,
are being attacked and robbed
of money and valuables.
The people on the boat
who were victimized
unanimously claim that the damage
was done by the "Demon of the Ocean."
And exterminating this Demon
of the Ocean is the mission?
Well, more or less, yes.
But there's more.
The Land of Sea does not have
a hidden village of its own,
so they're prepared for contingencies
through military cooperation
with the neighbouring Land of Water,
and have been paying them
a retainer every month.
However, the other day,
one of their ships that collects funds
was attacked
by the Demon of the Ocean as well.
I see. To preserve their relationship
with Land of Water,
Land of Sea will do anything
to protect the next ship.
Yes. This mission is to guard
the ships collecting funds
and destroy the Demon of the Ocean.
I've got a few people to work under you,
so I'm counting on you.
Work under me?
Enter!
The Chunin Exam's...
That scary proctor!
Oh, you're bringing back memories..!
Mitarashi Anko-sensei?
Why are you here?
— Everyone!
— Yes!
I'm pronouncing your mission!
Aburame Shino! Yamanaka Ino!
Uzumaki Naruto!
The three of you will work under Anko
and accompany her on a mission!
What?! These members?
The team is pretty disjointed, isn't it?!
No use talking about it!
Listen, I've thought the matter through
and I believe that this combination is
the most qualified for this mission.
Display your own capabilities to the
fullest extent and execute this mission!
Yes!
She just gathered the available Genin.
Really, she is such a...
Still, something doesn't feel
quite right...
Yeah, yeah, no complaints
about a mission that's settled!
Ouch! I got it!
Okay, we'll depart right away!
Everyone prepare and assemble
at the front gate!
— Roger!
Oh, ouch.
Anko.
Be careful.
Yes.
"Characteristics
of the Demon of the Ocean.
It's like a fish, like a person..."
What is this?!
Ah, someone's eyes are playing tricks.
Something like that can't exist!
Not true, it's possible
that Ex-Ninja become pirates
and use Transformation and Genjutsu.
Well, whatever, if we don't gather
information, there will be no solution.
Right.
Mother Island is the biggest island
at the center of Land of Sea.
We'll go to a nearby fishing port
and cross over by boat!
I understand!
Yeah! Let's depart for the Land of Sea!
This guy is always hyper.
I'm anxious about what's going to happen.
Here you are.
Um... Tsunade-sama.
It's about Mitarashi Anko just now.
Did...?
Did something happen in the past?
Sort of.
This is...
Her record of missions from about
the age of 10 is pretty sporadic.
Because Anko was under Orochimaru.
So, the parts that are blacked out
are combined
with Orochimaru's movements...
and in the confidential file?
Part of them are.
There are some parts
that aren't recorded.
That's the truth.
No record?! Even though
Anko herself was in the village?
That Orochimaru...
It seems he really didn't want
to be traced.
When he left the village,
he erased part of Anko's memories.
The wind is salty.
Coming this far, we can already see
over the Land of Sea.
Then, that must be the Mother Island?
What...? What is this feeling?
Everyone... Sorry, but...
Go ahead and take care
of the arrangements for the boat.
What? But what would you do, Sensei?
I'll take care of some business
and join you. See you!
Oh! Sensei?!
Come on, it can't be helped.
What are you doing, Shino?
We'll leave you behind!
Yeah.
The Curse Mark aches.
This presence... No question about it.
This way?
I can say their names
without a problem!
Um... That's Mother Island.
These are Taro Island and Jiro island.
And... that there's Demon Island!
Seems you prepared before you came.
I want to become a wiser, stronger
Shinobi like you, Orochimaru-sama.
Oh...?
Here.
Sorry, but I can't give you anything
more than this.
What's up, Ino?
Hey, mister!
Aren't you bringing prices down
way too much?
That's high-quality fish, isn't it?
Oh, dear.
I'm not price-cutting.
See, because of that
"Demon of the Ocean" uproar,
customers are completely staying away.
This is the market price around here.
Really? That fish is rarely...
What's with her appearance?
Is she injured or something?
No. That girl, she has her reasons.
Well...
she's a female diver from a small town
on the cape of Mother Island.
What?!
Why would a woman diver on
Mother Island transfer islands on purpose?
That's because the island people
didn't want to do business with her.
That girl,
in the past, she was spirited away.
"Spirited away"?
A person suddenly disappears.
Is that it?
That's right!
In the past,
a lot of island people disappeared
from being spirited away.
The story is that out of all those people
that girl was the only one
who suddenly returned one day.
Hey, hey!
It's a little village,
so everyone felt creepy.
They say that now she lives alone
outside of the village.
I see. I feel sorry for her.
With her appearance...
And then you hear things, I, too...
feel a little bit creepy.
That's true.
Hey, where's Naruto?
I don't know.
Hey! What are you guys doing?!
Oh, no!
— Hey, are you okay?
— Yes.
You're... You're from a place
called Mother Island, aren't you?
Nothing.
Ninja.
Oh, I'll help!
That's okay.
Huh? Hey, wait.
What the...?
It's too bad, but the last boat
from the port has already left.
But the sun hasn't even set yet.
Around here, there's nobody who will
take you across in the early evening.
Sorry, but come back tomorrow.
No way.
Well, is there a way to get
to Mother Island besides the ferry?
I can't really advise it, but...
If it's necessary,
I'll let you borrow my little boat.
Hey! I was looking all over for you guys!
Come on! Where were you?!
Sorry, sorry.
You should at least say something
before you disappear.
You and Sensei are exactly alike,
suddenly going someplace.
Feels like there'll be
a bumpy road ahead.
What?! That's rude.
Placing me in the same category together
with that unreasonable sensei...!
— Who's what?
— Sorry.
This sensei is dangerous, after all.
Good work procuring the boat!
Sensei, where in the world
have you been all this time?
Oh, something like gathering information.
Well, let's go!
The Shinobi of Leaf Village are here.
Land of Sea must have pleaded with them
to investigate
on the "Demon of the Ocean."
Well, then, we should give them
the best welcome.
It's getting dark.
We're almost to Mother Island.
All right, all right!
Full-speed advance to Mother Island!
Although the sun has already set...
Where does all
your hyper-energy come from?!
Times like this,
your state of mind is important!
Sakura sure has her share of trouble.
I feel sorry for her.
What the...?
I ran up against a rock or something!
Hang in there, Naruto!
Hey, all of you look forward, front!
Dodge it, quick!
You say that, but...
It's no good, the oar won't move!
I'll help!
You...! Striking Shadow Snake!
Naruto! Leave it!
I understand!
To show themself so soon...
That was close.
The two of you be careful!
He's aiming at us from underwater!
Damn it!
Demon of the Ocean or whatever,
an underwater creature
for an underwater battle!
Summoning Jutsu!
I'm counting on you, Chief Toad!
What?!
Hey! Naruto!
What kind of place did you call me to?!
Why did you come out?!
You stupid frog!
Oh! Hey, wait!
Summoning Jutsu.
Please come out, Chief Toad!
Hey, good evening!
It can't be!
I've been calling for Chief Toad!
Stupid! If you summoned
the old man to a place like this,
terrible things would happen.
Huh? Why?
We're freshwater creatures!
We don't go with saltwater!
I don't like salty things either.
You're no help at all!
Shino! Take care of Ino.
Okay!
All right! Fire Style: Dragon Flame Jutsu!
Water Clone?!
You let your guard down!
You did, too!
Take that!
There was one more?!
What the...? My body strength is...!
How is it?
My improved skill of Chakra Suction?
What's happening?!
Where did he go? Damn it!
My visibility is too poor.
Hey, pull yourself together, Naruto!
Big Brother, it itches.
Ah, I'm at my limit, too.
Big Brother!
This is not so good.
— Naruto!
— What happened?
You two are...?!
I'll discharge all the Chakra
I absorbed at once.
Water Style: Furious Current Jutsu!
Shoot! I can't approach them
so easily with this.
Naruto...
I can't stand this!
kaze ga fuite aa
the wind blows
itai kienai omoi
the pain, the memories won't disappear
nani wo motte ikou ka
what should be brought along?
atsumete hitotsu
assemble them into a piece
nido to nai nido to nai
there is no second chance, never
suteru nante baka mitai
how foolish it is to throw away
mujaki ni natte aa
acting so innocently
imeeji
the images
kitto sore wa owaranai
it probably will not end
ai no mune kogase
burn that love-filled heart
sen no yume watare
sail across a thousand dreams
juuoumujin kakete
running freely
te ni tsukamu sekai
to take hold of the world in hand
kumo ga chigirete
the clouds scatter
hi ga mata ochite
the sun sets yet again
hitori no pareedo ga ugokidasu
the solo parade begins to move
bouken kichijitsu shinpaku joushou
adventure, lucky day, geart beat, rising
meian souguu seimei souai
decisive, encounter, life, mutual love
To think the departure of
the collection ship
would be moved up
at the time like this.
It can't be helped.
We've got to find Naruto somehow
by tomorrow morning.
I hope we pick up some information about
the Demon of the Ocean along the way.
The search range is quite expansive, huh?
It'd be best to split up.
Then I'll go from the south,
you guys take the north.
— Roger!
Think about what happened yesterday.
Each of you, tackle this with care. Scatter!
Next time:
"Shock, the Closed Door."